in 1962 Rachel Carson animated the
national conversation with Silent Spring
an explosive book describing the
environmental Havoc rre by
DDT a moment in time with Dan
Roberts at first DDT Doral d TR
chloroethane seemed a miracle modern
agricultural practices had produced
increased crop yields but had also
opened the way to Greater infestation by
insect pests various chemical
insecticides were tried but not until
the late 1930s did there appear to be a
true solution to the problem of insect
control immediately upon USDA approval
of DDT for use on plants and
agricultural Commodities Farmers
snatched it up and crop production sword
by interrupting respiration at the
cellular level the grayish white powder
killed virtually every insect that
consumed it the insects literally
suffocated From the Inside Out DDT was
used extensively some would say
indiscriminately in the Years following
World War II but then the problems began
to surface the compound is very
effective poison against insects but in
sufficient quantities also against bird
birds and squirrels and humans sometimes
and the family cat furthermore DDT is
biologically persistent meaning that it
decomposes very slowly over many years
it remains in the environment and is
stored in fat grasshoppers Dying by the
millions in a field are snatched up by
field mice they in turn are eaten by
predatory birds and so on up the food
chain finally DDT also kills all the
good good nonpest insects many of which
before DDT had eaten the pests naturally
with no negative impact crop damage from
pest infestation actually eventually
increased following the adoption of DDT
in 1962 author and biologist Rachel
Carson released Silent Spring the book
was a sensation and provoked calls for
reform 11 years later in 1973 the US SDA
banned the use of DDT in the United
States the controversy however went a
long way toward sparking the modern
environmental movement Rachel Carson
never saw the full impact of her work
she died in
1964 at the University of Richmond I'm
Dan Roberts
[Music]
oh